This video will show you how to use Seller Central to find products for advertising based on your
business goals.
Let's look at three different ways to identify products for advertising in Seller Central.
We'll cover finding new products, managing inventory levels, and building on your successful products.
First goal?
Increase awareness of new products.
Advertising can help shoppers discover your newly listed products on Amazon.
Let's look at where to find these opportunities in Seller Central.
To find newly listed products, go to the Seller Central menu,
select Growth, and select Growth Opportunities.
From the Sell New Products tab, choose Launch Preset Sponsored Products Ad, New ASIN, from the drop-
down.
This dashboard shows recommendations for products listed in the last 90 days.
The recommendations update daily, and completed recommendations are removed after 24 hours.
Preset Sponsored Products campaigns include pre-populated settings for
daily budget, bidding strategy, targeting strategy, and suggested bids.
To review settings, select Launch Preset Sponsored Products Ad.
Choose Review and Launch in Ad Console to make adjustments, then launch the campaign in the Ads
Console.
Second goal?
Increase sales of existing products.
One strategy is to focus on products with excess inventory.
Using advertising for products with excess inventory can help increase product visibility,
manage inventory levels, and reduce additional storage costs for FBA sellers.
To find products with excess inventory, go to Seller Central and select FBA Inventory.
Sort your products by estimated excess units to identify opportunities.
Alternative method?
Go to Growth Opportunities.
Select Reduce Costs drop-down and choose Reduce excess inventory.
Sponsored Products Ad.
Third goal?
Build your brand and encourage repeat purchases.
Consider advertising products that already show strong performance.
To find these, select Reports.
Choose Business Reports.
Open the Brand Performance Report, then sort by Sales Rank to see your top performing products.
Advertising high-performing products can help maintain their visibility
and reach shoppers who may be interested in other products in your catalog.
You can also build brand loyalty by advertising your deals and promotions.
When you combine deals with advertising, you can help more shoppers discover your promotional offers
and enjoy your products.
To find deal opportunities, go to Advertising, then select Deals.
For products with active or upcoming deals, select the Edit drop-down, choose Create Ads,
then follow the prompts to set up your campaign.
Ready to get started?
Visit Seller Central today at sellercentral.
amazon.
com.
Already know what you want to advertise?
Create an account or sign in to Amazon Ads at advertising.
amazon.
com.